Benjamin D. Killeen

Ph.D. Student, Johns Hopkins University
Department of Computer Science
3400 N Charles St
Baltimore, MD 21218, USA
killeen@jhu.edu

★ benjamindkilleen.com - ♣ arcade.cs.jhu.edu - ♣ cirl.lcsr.jhu.edu
Benjamin D. Killeen - ● 0000-0003-2511-7929 - ♠ benjamindkilleen
● @bdkilleen - ■ benjamindkilleen - ■ @benjamindkilleen

Summary

A Ph.D. Student at Johns Hopkins University, I am interested in intelligent surgical systems based on explorative computer vision and deep reinforcement learning that directly improve patient outcomes. I am a member of the Advanced Robotics and Computationally Augmented Environments (ARCADE) research group and the Computational Interaction and Robotics Laboratory (CIRL).

Education

Ph.D., Computer Science, Johns Hopkins University, Baltimore, MD, USA.08/2019 - presentWith Mathias Unberath and Gregory D. Hager.

B.A., Computer Science with Honors (Physics Minor), University of Chicago, Chicago, IL, USA. 09/2015 - 06/2019 Thesis: Starting from Scratch: Deep Learning for Novel Scientific Image Analysis With Gordon Kindlmann.

Research Experience

Research assistant, Department of Computer Science, Johns Hopkins University, Baltimore, MD, USA. 08/2020 - present With Mathias Unberath, Gregory D. Hager.

Research Assistant, Laboratory for Computational Sensing and Robotics, Johns Hopkins University, 08/2019 - 06/2020 Baltimore, MD, USA.

With Gregory D. Hager, Mathias Unberath, and Russel Taylor. Recipient: LCSR Fellowship for Outstanding Incoming Ph.D. Students.

Research assistant, Department of Computer Science, University of Chicago, Chicago, IL, USA. 03/2018 - 08/2019 With Gordon Kindlmann.

Professional Experience

Computer Vision / Al Intern, Applied Research, Intuitive Surgical Inc., Sunnyvale, CA, USA. 06/2020 - 07/2020 With Omid Mohareri.

Software Development Intern, Cognitive Computing, Epic Systems, Verona, WI, USA.

06/2018 - 08/2018

Research Intern, IBM Research - Almaden, San Jose, CA, USA.

06/2017 - 08/2017

With Geoffrey Burr.

Selected Honors

Best Presentation, Reliable Software Systems course, Johns Hopkins University, USA.04/2021Best Graduate Project Award, Computer Integrated Surgical Systems and Technology course, Johns Hopkins University, USA.05/2020COVID-19 Dataset Award, Kaggle.04/2020For our county-level dataset in [M-1].04/2020

Intuitive Surgical Best Project Award, Deep Learning course, Johns Hopkins University, USA.

12/2019
Project: Enriching Unsupervised Feature Learning via Intermediate Subtasks.

With Michael Peven, Shaoyan Pan, and Matthew Pittman.

Publications

My publication list is also available on Google Scholar. Asterisk (*) indicates equal contribution.

Peer-reviewed Journal Articles

A. Hundt, **B. Killeen**, H. Kwon, C. Paxton, GD Hager. "Good Robot!": Efficient Reinforcement Learning for Multi-Step Visual Tasks with Sim to Real Transfer. IEEE Robotics and Automation Letters, vol. 5, no. 4, pp. 6724–6731, Oct. 2020. doi: 10.1109/LRA.2020.3015448.

S. Ambrogio, P. Narayanan, H. Tsai, R. M. Shelby, I. Boybat, C. di Nolfo, S. Sidler, M. Giordano, M. Bodini, N. Farinha, **B. Killeen**, C. Cheng, Y. Jaoudi, G. W. Burr. Equivalent-accuracy accelerated neural-network training using analogue memory. Nature, vol. 558, no. 7708, p. 60, Jun. 2018. doi: 10.1038/s41586-018-0180-5.

Peer-reviewed Conference Papers

X. Liu*, **B. D. Killeen***, A. Sinha, M. Ishii, G. Hager, R. Taylor, M. Unberath. Neighborhood Normalization for Robust Geometric Feature Learning. To appear in The IEEE/CVF Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition, 2021.

1_2

J-1

	C. Gao, X. Liu, W. Gu, B. D. Killeen , M. Armand, R. Taylor, M. Unberath. Generalizing Spatial Transformers to Projective Geometry with Applications to 2D/3D Registrationc. MICCAI, 2020, arxiv:2003.10987.	C-2
	X. Liu, Y. Zhang, B. Killeen , M. Ishii, G. Hager, R. Taylor, M. Unberath. Extremely Dense Point Correspondences using a Learned Feature Descriptor. Proceedings of the IEEE/CVF Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition, pp. 4847-4856, 2020.	C-1
Preprints	J. Y. Wu*, B. D. Killeen *, P. Nikutta, M. Thies, A. Zapaishchykova, S. Chakraborty, M. Unberath. Changes in Reproductive Rate of SARS-CoV-2 Due to Non-pharmaceutical Interventions in 1,417 U.S. Counties. medRxiv preprint, Jun. 2020, doi: 10.1101/2020.05.31.20118687.	M-2
	B. D. Killeen* , J. Y. Wu * , K. Shah, A. Zapaishchykova, P. Nikutta, A. Tamhane, S. Chakraborty, J. Wei, T. Gao, M. Thies, M. Unberath. A County-level Dataset for Informing the United States' Response to COVID-19. arXiv preprint, 2020, arXiv:2004.00756.	M-1
Patents	G. W. Burr and B. D. Killeen . 2020. Efficient Processing of Convolutional Neural Network Layers Using Analog-memory-based Hardware. 20200117986, filed March 25, 2019, and issued April 16, 2020, uspto.report/patent/app/20200117986.	P-1
Selected Press	Dziarkach, Andrei. "Details with Andrei Dziarkach." Voice of America. November 21, 2020 Accessed November 26, 2020. golosameriki.com/a/detali/5671254.html.	2020
	Rosen, Jill. "Dog Training Methods Help JHU Teach Robots to Learn New Tricks." The Johns Hopkins University Hub. The Johns Hopkins University, October 26, 2020. hub.jhu.edu/2020/10/26/positive-reinforcementfor-robots.	
Teaching		
Assistant Teaching	Machine Learning and Large Scale Data Analysis, Department of Computer Science, University of Chicago, Chicago, IL, USA With Prof. Yali Amit.	03/2019 - 06/2019
	Wrote supplementary course material and held weekly lab sessions.	
	Selected review: "Ben was incredibly patient during office hours and always responsive to student questions. In addition, he often presented demos during office hours or showed easier ways to handle the homework assignments; both were very helpful." More reviews available at benjamindkilleen.com/teaching/2019-spring-lsda	
Grading	Department of Computer Science, University of Chicago, Chicago, IL, USA - Scientific Visualization - Introduction to Computer Science I - Introduction to Computer Science II	01/2019 - 08/2019
Tutoring	Topics in Computer Science, Machine Learning , Baltimore, MD, USA. I tutor young people (middle- and high-school age) who are interested in CS and ML. More info at benjamindkilleen.com/teaching/2020-tutoring.	06/2020 - present
Supervision	I have supervised a number of talented masters and undergraduate students on research projects and theses:	
	Nethra Venkatayogi, The University of Texas at Austin, Austin, TX, USA.	05/2021 - present
	Max Judish, Brown University, Providence, RI, USA.	01/2021 - present
	Shreya Chakraborty, Johns Hopkins University, Baltimore, MD, USA.	08/2020 - present
	Philipp Nikutta, Technical University of Munich, Munich, Germany.	12/2019 - 03/2020
Service	Graduate Student Committee Representative , Laboratory for Computational Sensing and Robotics, Baltimore, MD, USA.	2020 - present
	Volunteer Instructor, CompileHer, Chicago, IL, USA.	2019
Peer Review	- IEEE/CVF Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR)	2021
	- Nature Scientific Data	2020

Reliable Software Systems Theory of Computation Parallel Programming Nonlinear Optimization II Computer Integrated Surgery II Computer Integrated Surgery I Deep Learning

Undergraduate Unsupervised Learning*

Computer Vision

Machine Learning and Large Scale Data Analysis

Operating Systems Honors Combinatorics Honors Algorithms Honors Discrete Mathematics Scientific Visualization Programming Languages

Networks and Distributed Systems Quantum Mechanics I \& II Intermediate Mechanics

Electronics Wizards

*Graduate level.

Memberships IEEE Graduate Student Member

2020 - present

Extracurricular In my spa

In my spare time, I enjoy running, climbing, and making visual art. I also write creatively:

Creative nonfiction: benjamindkilleen.medium.com

Science Fiction: novel in progress.

Metadata

This document is available

 $\hbox{- online: benjamind} killeen.com/markdown-cv.\\$

- as a PDF: benjamindkilleen.com/files/cv.pdf.

Created based on markdown-cv by Eliseo Papa with styles based on David Whipp.

MIT License.

Last updated: May 2021

GPA: 3.81